Kent Shaffer

Software Engineer

Portfolio

https://kentshaffer.github.io/react_portfolio/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kent-shaffer-2b26b795?trk=people-guest_people_search-card

GitHub

https://github.com/kentshaffer

SUMMARY

Front-end/full-stack web developer. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from UC San Diego. Ready to combine past customer service experience, problem solving, and newly acquired web development skills in order to create user centered web applications.

EXPERIENCE

Bird Rock Coffee Roasters, San Diego — *Lead Barista*

SEP 2021 - PRESENT

- Received an average rating of 4.7 out of 5 by recommending products to meet individual customer needs and preferences.
- Minimized customer wait time by monitoring supply levels at bar and customer areas to meet typical demands.
- Maintained inventory organization by complying with standards for merchandising, stocking, and storing products in order to improve workflow.

Moss Bay Kayak Paddle Board & Sail Center, Seattle — *General Manager*

OCT 2018 - AUG 2021

- Supervised and effectively trained 20–30 employees per season to decrease rental wait time and boost daily rental revenue.
- Scheduled, organized, and led group rentals and kayak tours to ensure customer satisfaction with each step in the process.
- Maintained and made necessary repairs to rental equipment and dock structure to insure that the rental facility was safe for customers and the equipment was fully functional.

Moss Bay Kayak Paddle Board & Sail Center, Seattle — *Director of Program Operations*

OCT 2017 - SEP 2018

- Trained and supervised new camp counselors in operations practices and camper-focused water activities to provide a safe and organized environment for the campers
- Monitored camper behavior during activities to effectively handle discipline situations and encourage positive behavior.
- Communicated with parents and camp staff regarding children or program issues to set and meet expectations, as well as answer any questions.
- Supervised young campers in recreational activities such as kayaking, paddle boarding, and sailing, creating a safe and fun learning environment.

Moss Bay Kayak Paddle Board & Sail Center, Seattle — Camp Counselor & Rental Staff Member

MAY 2017 - SEP 2017

- Taught campers water-based skills such as sailing, kayaking and paddle boarding to increase campers' self-reliance and confidence.
- Collaborated with other camp counselors to design fun and enriching learning activities for campers.

San Diego, CA 92110 (360)689-6645 kentshaff@gmail.com

SKILLS

Troubleshooting

Teamwork & Collaboration

Responsive Design

API Structures

Customer Service

Problem Solving

Object Oriented Programming

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

React.js

MySQL

MongoDB

Node.js

Express.js.

- Supervised groups of campers through a variety of camp activities to ensure camper safety.
- Instructed rental customers on paddling techniques and water basics based on individual skill levels to ease anxiety, answer any questions, and create eagerness and excitement about spending time on the water.

PROJECTS

Instacook | https://github.com/CMolitor96/instacook | https://frozen-chamber-50604.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Instacook is a recipe sharing app that allows users to save and share
 their favorite recipes. It features user authentication and users are able to see top
 posted recipes on the homepage, and all of their own posted recipes on their user
 profile.
- Role: Team member Front end
- Tools: React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React-Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo-Server, Mongoose, MongoDB, JWT, Bcrypt, Heroku

NoSQL social network api | https://github.com/kentshaffer/nosql_social_network_api | https://watch.screencastify.com/v/Q7s7704JF2KXaKCuMijH

- Summary: Backend API structure for a social media app. The API build is
 capable of creating and deleting users, connecting friends to, and deleting friends
 from a given user, allowing users to post, edit, and delete thoughts, and allowing
 users to add and delete comments from a user's posted thoughts.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Insomnia

¡GOOOL! | https://github.com/kentshaffer/goool | https://secure-shore-30155.herokuapp.com/login

- Summary: ¡GOOOL! is a personalized goal tracking app. The app features user authentication. All goals are displayed on the user's homepage so the user is able to see past and open goals. Users are able to create goals and the associated todo list to accomplish said goal. A counter displays the number of days since goal creation, and as users check off todos, their goal progress bar updates in real time
- Role: Team member Front end
- Tools: JavaScript, Node.js, Handlebars.js, CSS, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, doteny, Luxon, Canvas-Confetti

EDUCATION

UCSD, San Diego — Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

Seattle Pacific University, Seattle — *B.A. Christian Theology*JAN 2015 - JUN 2017

Olympic College, Bremerton —Associate of Arts

SEP 2012 - JUN 2014